# Joe Schlick

Auburn, California, United States



in linkedin.com/in/joe-schlick-664b503a



ioe@doggedprods.com



https://joeschlick.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/



+1 415.377.6370

### Summary

I am currently enrolled in the UC Davis Coding Bootcamp for full stack web development, and I am scheduled to graduate December 15, 2020.

I have been a freelance producer and coordinator in the corporate event industry since 2009. I have also worked on sets and props in the San Francisco film industry since 1999.

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:

- The Cynical Travelers Guide To 2020: Enter a city and state, and get weather and breaking news plus COVID 19 Data. Delivered with a dark sense of humor. Tech used: JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, HTML, Foundation, CSS.
- Weather Dashboard: Current weather plus a 5 day forecast for entered city. Saves searches for future reference. Tech used: JavaScript, ¡Query, APIs, HTML.
- Day Planner: Enter and save activities for the day. Time fields are colored based on past, present, or future entries. Tech used: JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, HTML.

Technical Skills: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node JS, Mac OS, G Suite, Microsoft Office, Sketchup, Illustrator, Photoshop.

Specialties: Production, production management, project management

### **Experience**



### Virtual Event Producer

Digitell, Inc.

Jul 2020 - Present (2 months +)

Wirecast / Zoom Tech for virtual events.



### Speaker Coordinator

#### **FNTECH**

Apr 2015 - Mar 2020 (5 years)

# Act as a point of contact for all speakers—General Session and/or Breakouts

# Add and edit session and speaker information on the show website and in the registration database

# Manage speaker support slide decks and make sure they are submitted for client approval

# Set up rehearsal times and communicate logistics information to presenters before they arrive onsite

# Manage speaker support onsite and ensure that all speakers have successful sessions

#2017, 2020 - OCP Global Summit - San Jose, CA

#2017, 2019 - Oculus Connect - San Jose, CA

# 2015 - 2017 - OpenStack Summit - Multiple US and International Cities

#2015 - 2016 - Facebook F8 - San Francisco, CA

#2015 - 2016 - Facebook People@ - San Jose, CA

### **Furniture and Decor Producer**

Jack Morton Worldwide

- Jun 2014 Mar 2020 (5 years 10 months)
- # Work with creative team to select furniture that fits their design vision
- # Create furniture decks to present options to client
- # Manage furniture budget, delivery, onsite distribution, and pickup for very large shows
- # Personal relationship with a wide variety of vendors
- # 2014-2019 VMware VMworld Las Vegas, NV and San Francisco, CA
- #2019 Google Next San Francisco, CA
- #2018 Google Engage Anaheim, CA

# Producer

#### Jack Morton Worldwide

- Jul 2011 Mar 2020 (8 years 9 months)
- # Work with client and creative team to achieve overall vision for event
- # Hire crew leads and engage vendors
- # Manage overall budget
- # Manage onsite production and last-minute changes
- # 2013 2017 HP Executive Forum Various cities
- # 2014 2016 HP PPSA Sales Training Various cities
- #2014 HP Commercial Sector Training Boise, ID
- # 2013 T-Mobile Shakira Concert New York, NY
- # 2013 T-Mobile MLB FanFest New York, NY
- # 2013 T-Mobile Press Event Un-Carrier Launch New York, NY
- # 2013 T-Mobile CES Press Event, Las Vegas, NV
- # 2012 T-Mobile Challenger Tour Multi-city training event
- # 2012 Samsung Galaxy S3 Training Tour Multi-city training event
- # 2011 T-Mobile Training Tour Multi-city training event

# F Graphics Producer

#### Freeman Company

Aug 2016 - Nov 2019 (3 years 4 months)

- # Work with client and creative teams to create graphics for speaker support, signage, and/or video
- # Manage the creation of graphic assets with graphic artists
- # Manage budget for graphics creation
- # Manage media assets for general sessions / Manage onsite signage distribution
- # 2016-2019 Dreamforce Executive Summit San Francisco, CA

# opus Deck Manager / Assistant Stage Manager

#### Opus Agency

May 2019 - Oct 2019 (6 months)

- # Plan and manage onstage furniture placement and stage moves
- # Supervise local labor stage hands/carpenters as needed for all stage moves
- # Assist producer as directed in talent management, cueing, and other related needs for running show and rehearsals
- # 2019 | Google I/O: Keynote and Breakout Sessions, Shoreline Amphitheater, Mountain View, CA
- # 2019 Google Hardware Keynote Session, New York, NY
- # 2019 Google GDC Keynote Session, San Francisco, CA

# Deck Manager / Assistant Stage Manager

### Level 2 Design, inc

May 2016 - Oct 2019 (3 years 6 months)

# Plan and manage onstage furniture placement and stage moves

- # Supervise local labor stage hands/carpenters as needed for all stage moves
- # Assist producer as directed in talent management, cueing, and other related needs for running show and rehearsals

# 2017-2018 - Google I/O: Keynote and Breakout Sessions, Shoreline Amphitheater, Mountain View, CA

# Oeck Manager / Assistant Stage Manager

#### Jack Morton Worldwide

Sep 2015 - Sep 2019 (4 years 1 month)

- # Plan and manage onstage furniture placement and stage moves
- # Supervise local labor stage hands/carpenters as needed for all stage moves
- # Assist producer as directed in talent management, cueing, and other related needs for running show and rehearsals
- # 2017-2019 Google Zeitgeist Phoenix, AZ
- # 2019 Youtube GBS Keynote Los Angeles, CA

### XDA Producer

### The XD Agency

May 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 2 months)

- # Manage onsite production and last-minute changes
- # 2017-2019 Cisco Live General Session Various cities
- # 2018 Kia Press Event New York Auto Show New York, NY
- # 2017 Kia Press Event LA Auto Show, Los Angeles, CA

# Producer

### **Drury Design**

Feb 2019 - Feb 2019 (1 month)

# Onsite Producer - IBM Think 2019 - San Francisco, CA

# Producer

### George P Johnson Experience Marketing

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018 (3 months)

# Onsite Producer - 2018 Square Enix Final Fantasy 14 Fan Festival - Las Vegas, NV

# Onsite Producer - 2018 Capcom Cup - Las Vegas, NV

# Deck Manager / Assistant Stage Manager

### Freeman Company

Sep 2015 - Sep 2018 (3 years 1 month)

- # Plan and manage onstage furniture placement and stage moves
- # Supervise local labor stage hands/carpenters as needed for all stage moves
- # Assist producer as directed in talent management, cueing, and other related needs for running show and rehearsals
- # 2015-2018 Splunk .conf. Keynote Session Various cities
- #2015 Marketo Nation Summit Keynote Session San Francisco, CA

# Graphics and Media Manager

#### **FNTECH**

Mar 2017 - Apr 2017 (2 months)

- # Tracking and managing edits for Keynote Session speaker support and videos
- # Maintaining version control
- # Trafficking updated content to presentation technicians
- #2017 Facebook F8, San Jose, CA

# XDA Graphics Producer

The XD Agency

Jan 2017 - Jan 2017 (1 month)

# Managed Production of slide deck and animations for Intel COO's Keynote Presentation

#2017 - Intel Sales Meeting, Anaheim, CA

#### **ENWOOD** Producer

### The Kenwood Group

Feb 2014 - Jun 2016 (2 years 5 months)

# Work with client and creative team to achieve overall vision for event

# Hire crew leads and engage vendors

# Manage overall budget

# Manage orders and other paperwork for trade show booths

# Manage onsite production and last-minute changes

# 2016 - Capcom, Main Booth at E3 - Los Angeles, CA

# 2015 - Square Enix, Judges Night - Los Angeles, CA

# 2015 - Square Enix, Deus Ex Demo Theater at E3 - Los Angeles, CA

# 2015 - Square Enix, Final Fanstasy 15 Press Event - Los Angeles, CA

# 2014 - Square Enix, Final Fantasy 14 Fan Festival - Las Vegas, NV

# 2014 - Square Enix, Nosgoth Lounge at E3 - Los Angeles, CA

### N Deck Manager / Assistant Stage Manager

### **AV Concepts**

Oct 2015 - May 2016 (8 months)

# Plan and manage onstage furniture placement and stage moves

# Supervise local labor stage hands/carpenters as needed for all stage moves

# Assist producer as directed in talent management, cueing, and other related needs for running show and rehearsals

# 2016 - Google I/O: Keynote and Breakout Sessions, Shoreline Amphitheater, Mountain View, CA

#2015-2016 - Google Zeitgeist - Phoenix, AZ

#### Associate Producer

#### Kaleidoscope Productions

Jun 2009 - Aug 2012 (3 years 3 months)

# 2010-2012 - Toyota National Dealers Meeting - Las Vegas, NV

Worked directly with the client executives and the graphics team to translate their ideas into visual concepts.

# 2010–2012 - HP VIP Experience, Paul McCartney World Tour - 33 shows worldwide

Supervised the setup of a VIP suite for HP clients and guests at each venue on the tour.

# 2009-2010 - In house post production coordinator - San Francisco, CA

Managed scheduling, traffic flow, and budgeting for post production of corporate videos for HP.

# Art Director / Set Decorator / Prop Master / Lead Man

### **Various Companies**

Sep 1999 - Jul 2012 (12 years 11 months)

See the attached PDF for a selected list of film credits.

### **Education**



### **UC Davis Continuing and Professional Education**

Bootcamp - Full Stack Web Development

2020 - 2020

# Santa Fe University of Art and Design

B.A., Moving Image Arts 1996 - 1999

# Lewis & Clark College

Art

1993 - 1995

### **Skills**

Production Managment • Illustrator • Photoshop • Microsoft Office • Project Management • SketchUp • Mac • Art Direction • Film • Corporate Events